A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich papers FA135
Rockefeller Archive Center
Paul Ehrlich papers
1878 to present
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Ehrlich, Paul
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA135
43 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Paul Ehrlich, 1854-1915, physician and scientist, Berlin and Frankfurt, Germany. Founder of hematology, pioneer and major contributor to the fields of histochemistry and immunology. Famous for his development of chemotherapy (arsphenamine - 606) for syphilis. Nobel Laureate in physiology or medicine in 1908, jointly with Elie Metchnikoff for their studies in immunity.
Biographical note
1854 Born March 14 in Strehlen, Silesia
1872 Graduated from St. Maria Magdalena Gymnasium in Breslau
1878 M.D. from the University of Leipzig, after studies at the Universities of Breslau, Strassburg and Freiburg
1878-1888 Assistant physician, later senior physician at the Charité Hospital in Berlin, director Professor von Frerichs
1888/1889 After contracting tuberculosis cured in Italy and Egypt
1889 Established a small private research laboratory in Berlin
1890 Appointment in the Robert Koch Institute for Infectious Diseases in Berlin
1896 Appointed director of the new State Institute for Serum Research and Serum Control in Steglitz, a suburb of Berlin
1898 This institute moved to Frankfurt and was expanded and renamed: The Institute for Experimental Therapy
1906 The Georg-Speyer wing for chemotherapeutical research was added with the private financial help of Mrs. Franzisca Speyer
1908 Nobel Prize in physiology and medicine
1911 Received the state rank of "Wirklicher Geheimer Rath" with the title of Excellency
1914 Named "Ordentlicher Professor" at the newly founded University of Frankfurt
1915 August 20, died in Bad Homburg and is buried in the Jewish Cemetery in Frankfurt
Honorary Degrees
1904 University of Chicago, LL.D.
1907 University of Oxford, D.C.L.
1911 University of Athens, Dr. phil. h.c.
1911 University of Breslau, Dr. med. h.c.
Awards
1887 Senckenberg Naturforschende Gesellschaft, Frankfurt a.M. Tiedemann Prize
1903 The Prussian Great-Golden Medal of Science
1906 Prize of Honor at the XVth International Congress of Medicine at Lisbon
1908 Nobel Prize
1911 Liebig Medal, Society of German Chemists
1914 Cameron Prize of Edinburgh
Orders: Bavaria: Member of the Bavarian Maximilian Order, Denmark: Commander Cross of the Dannebrog Order, Second Class, Japan: Order of the Rising Sun, Third Degree, Norway: Commander Cross of the Royal Norwegian St. Olaf Order, Second Degree, Palatinate: Cavalier Cross of the order of Berthold I of Zähringen, Prussia: Order of the Crown, Second Degree; Order of the Red Eagle, Second Degree, Rumania: Cross for Sanitary Merits, First Degree, Russia: Order of St. Anne, First Degree, with Diamonds, Star and Cross, Serbia: Great Cross of the Order of St. Sava, Spain: Great Cross of the Order of Alfonso XII, with Star and Cross, Venezuela: Order of the Bust of Bolivar, Second Degree, with Precious Stones
Membership in Scientific Societies (83)
1887 Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellachaft, Frankfurt a.M., Corresponding Member
1899 Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellechaft, Frankfurt a.M., Ordinary Member
1900 Balneologische Gesellschaft, Berlin, Honorary Member
1900 Royal Danish Society of Sciences, Copenhagen, Foreign Member
1902 International Society for the Fight against Tuberculosis, Berlin, Honorary Member
1902 German Chemical Society, Berlin, Member of the Committee
1903 Silesian Society for Home Culture, Corresponding Member
1903 Royal Academy of Medicine, Turin, Corresponding Member
1904 Royal Academy of Sciences, Bologna, Corresponding Member
1904 Society for Internal Medicine, Vienna, Honorary Member
1904 Imperial and Royal Society of Physicians, Vienna, Honorary Member
1904 The New York Academy of Medicine, Honorary Member
1904 Royal Society of Sciences, Göttingen, Foreign Member of the mathematical and physical class
1904 Royal Society of Medicine and Natural Science, Brussels, Corresponding Member
1904 Academy of Sciences, Washington, Foreign Member
1904 Societas therapeutical Mosquana, Moscow, Honorary Member
1905 Académie de Médecine, Paris, Foreign Member
1905 Medical Society, Budapest, Honorary Member
1906 Medical Society of Finland, Helsingfors, Honorary Member
1906 Society, of Physicians, Munich, Honorary Member
1906 Société de Biologie, Paris, Ordinary Member
1907 Pathological Society of Great Britain and Ireland, Honorary Member
1907 Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, London, Honorary Member
1907 Royal Academy dei Lincei, Rome, Foreign Member
1907 Royal Institute of Public Health, London, Honorary Member
1907 Medical Society of Berlin, Honorary Member
1908 Société de Pathologie Exotique (Institut Pasteur), Paris, Honorary Member
1908 Physical-Medical Society, Erlangen, Honorary Member
1908 Society for the Knowledge of Nature and Medical Treatment, Dresden, Honorary Member
1908 Swedish Medical Society, Stockholm, Honorary Member
1908 Physical Society, Frankfurt, Honorary Member
1909 Medical Society, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member
1910 Microbiological Society, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member
1910 Royal Academy of Medicine, Turin, Honorary Member
1910 Royal Society, London, Honorary Member
1910 Société Médicale Impériale du Caucase, Honorary Member
1910 International Commission for the Study of the Causes of Mental Diseases and their Prophylaxis, Berlin, Honorary Member
1910 Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences, Stockholm, Foreign Member
1910 German Society for Tropical Medicine, Hamburg, Honorary Member
1910 Society of Physicians, Odessa, Honorary Member
1910 Société Khediviale de Médecine, Cairo, Honorary Member
1910 International Commission for the Study of the Causes of Mental Diseases and their Prophylaxis, Rome, Honorary Member
1910 Medical Society of Jekaterinoslaw, Honorary Member
1910 Vienna Dermatological Society, Honorary Member
1910 Medical Society of Serbia, Belgrade, Honorary Member
1910 Physico-Medical Society, Saratow, Honorary Member
1911 Union of the St. Petersbuerg Pediatricians, Honorary Member
1911 Société Imperiale de Médecine, Constantinople, Honorary Member
1911 Royal Society of Sciences, Upsala, Ordinary Member
1911 Academia Romana, Bucharest, Honorary Member
1911 Union of Physicians, Smolensk, Honorary Member
1911 Microbiological Society, Delft, Corresponding Member
1911 Royal Medical Society, Edinburgh, Honorary Member
1911 Academie Royal de Médecine, Brussels, Honorary Member
1911 Imperial Institute for Experimental Therapy, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member
1912 Physiological Society of London, Honorary Member
1912 Society of Internal Medicine, Berlin, Honorary Member
1912 Society of Cancer Research of the Palatinate, Heidelberg, Honorary Member
1912 Charkow Veterinary Institute, Honorary Member
1912 Society of Brazilian Dermatologists, Honorary President
1912 National Academy of Caracas, Corresponding Member
1912 City of Strehlen, Honorary Citizen
1912 Société Royale des Sciences médicales et naturelles, Brussels, Hon. Member
1912 German Society of Recreation Homes for Merchants, Member of Committee
1912 Dermatological Society, Odessa, Honorary Member
1912 Sommering-Prize Commission, Member
1912 Medical Society of Athens, Honorary Member
1913 Society for Natural Sciences, Braunschweig, Honorary Member
1913 German Chemical Society, Berlin, Honorary Member
1913 Union of Physicians, Archangel, Honorary Member
1913 Society of Physicians, Odessa, Honorary Member
1913 Society of German Physicians of Mental Diseases, Berlin, Honorary Member
1913 Medical Society of Orel
1913 Society of Veterinary Doctors of the Veterinary Institute of Kazan Hon. Member
1913 Harveian Society of London, Foreign Member
1913 Société de Biologie, Paris, Honorary Member
1913 Italian Society of Dermatologists and Physicians for Sexual Diseases, Rome, Honorary Member
1914 Medical-Surgical Society of Bologna, Corresponding Member
1914 Society of Specialists for Children, Moscow, Honorary Member
1914 Norwegian Society of Natural Sciences, Christiana, Foreign Member
1914 Society of Jewish Physicians of the Ottoman Empire, Constantinople, Honorary Member
1915 Pharmaceutical Society, Berlin, Honorary Member
The above information was copied from the book Paul Ehrlich, by Martha Marquardt. Henry Schuman, 951, pp 252-255.
Family Note
1883 August 14 Married Hedwig Pinkus
1884 October 19 Born daughter Stefanie (m. Ernst Schwerin)
1886 January 23 Born daughter Marianne (m. Edmund Landau)
Grandchildren: Hans-Wolfgang Schwerin; Gunther Schwerin; Herbert Landau; Dolly Landau; SuzanneLandau; Matthias Landau
Scope and Contents note
The Ehrlich papers, a special collection of the Rockefeller University, consists of copy books and their typescripts, laboratory notes, correspondence, photographs, books, diplomas, obituary material and memorabilia. There is very little incoming correspondence in this collection, although a synopsis of about 450 letters is available. This synopsis may have been prepared by Martha Marquardt, Paul Ehrlich's secretary for many years. Many original letters by Paul Ehrlich, both handwritten and typed, with his signature are part of this collection. These letters seem to have been collected by the recipients and returned to Mrs. Ehrlich after her husband's death. Mrs. Ehrlich may also have requested reminiscences about her husband by his friends and colleagues which she collected, hoping to yield suitable material for a biography at a later time.
The collection was given by the grandsons of Paul Ehrlich, Hans and Günther Schwerin, with the aim to establish a central Paul Ehrlich archive, since much of the material was dispersed during the war years. Mr. Günther Schwerin located the copy books right after the war in Germany and sent them and other material to the Wellcome Institute for the History of Medicine in London for safekeeping. Miss Marquardt, after having spent the war years in France, went to London and transcribed the copy books, since Ehrlich's handwriting is very hard to read and she was one of the few people who could do so. At that time Dr. F. Himmelweit, London, prepared the Collected Papers of Paul Ehrlich in four volumes. Pergamon Press published three volumes in 1960 (the fourth was never published) with and introduction by Sir Henry Dale, a friend and colleague of Paul Ehrlich.
Custodial History note
The present collection is made up of material from two sources:
1) the Wellcome Institute for the History of Medicine
2) a storage house in New York, where Mrs. Ehrlich's belongings were kept after her death in 1948.
It has now been fully integrated and no further distinction from which source it came has been preserved.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers of Paul Ehrlich were deposited with The Rockefeller University Archives on November 1978 by Mr. Günther Schwerin.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 650 Eh89
Conditions Governing Access note
Written permission must be obtained from the Head of Donor Relations/Collection Development of the Rockefeller Archive Center, or an applicable designee, in order to access the collection.
Biochemistry; Immunology; Blood; Syphilis; Medical sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Hematology; Rockefeller University; Ehrlich, Paul; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
- Correspondence, 1883 February-August
  Scope and Contents note
  Note: The letters written during the engagement months (February to August 1883) are listed separately; see box nos. 48 and 49.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Althoff, Friedrich, 1899-1907; mostly handwritten (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Althoff to Ehrlich, 12 letters
    - Ehrlich to Althoff, 4 letters
    - Hedwig Ehrlich to Althoff, 1 letter
  - Behring, Emil, 1894-1906 (Box 1, Folder 3, Folder 2)
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Ehrlich's draft of contract, 1894; handwritten
      Description of contract by Hedwig Ehrlich in a letter to her parents.
    - Behring's draft of contract, 1895; handwritten
    - Laubenheimer to Behring, 1 letter
    - Ehrlich to Behring, 1896; 7 letters handwritten
    - Behring to Ehrlich, 2 letters handwritten
    - Knorr to Ehrlich, 7 letters handwritten
    - Ehrlich to Behring, 1897; handwritten
    - Ehrlich's writing, 3 letters
    - Behring to Ehrlich, 2 letters handwritten
    - Behring to Liebreich, 1 letter typescript copy
    - Behring to Ehrlich, 1898; 5 letters handwritten
    - Behring to Ehrlich, 1899; 4 letters handwritten
    - Ehrlich to Solomonson, 1 letter typescript copy
    - Ehrlich's handwritten note, 1 letter
    - Enoch to Dönitz re Behring, 1903; 1 letter typescript
    - Behring to Enoch, 2 letters, typescript copies
    - Enoch to Behring, 2 letters, typescript copies
    - Enoch to Marx re. Behring, 1 letter typescript
    - Enoch correspondence
      Complete set of typescript copy.
    - Ehrlich to Althoff re Behring, 1906; typescript copy
    - Sheet with experiments in Behring and, undated
    - Ehrlich's handwriting, 5 photos of test tubes
  - Benda, Ludwig, 1907-1910; mostly handwritten (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Benda to Ehrlich, 4 letters
    - Ehrlich to Benda, 1 letter
  - Bertheim, Alfred, 1910; Typescript (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Ehrlich about Bertheim.
  - Bills and Receipts, 4 items, 2 in Ehrlich's hand (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cahn, Adolf Printed announcement of Goetz-Medal (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Darmstädter, Ludwig, 1910-1915; handwritten and typescript (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Darmstädter to Ehrlich, 17 letters
    - Ehrlich to Darmstädter, 12 letters
  - Dönitz, Wilhelm, 1899 1900; 11 letters handwritten (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Donitz to Ehrlich.
  - Ehrlich, Hedwig, 1896 1911 undated; handwritten (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Paul to Hedwig Ehrlich
    - (Hedwig's visit in Neustadt), 1896; 6 letters, 1 telegram
    - (Hedwig's visit in Switzerland), 1911; 8 letters
    - undated, 10 letters, 1 postcard
    - Althoff to Hedwig Ehrlich, 1 letter
  - Ehrlich, Stefanie undated, handwritten, 1 letter (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Ehrlich to Stefanie.
  - Elster (?), 1909; typescript (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Elster to Ehrlich.
  - Fränkel, Arthur, 1899; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Request by the military physician in Munich for a recommendation for Fränkel by Ehrlich.
  - Fudsimato, Tara, 1891; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Ehrlich's medical report on Fudsimato.
  - Goldschmid, undated; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Ehrlich's letter to someone with reference to Goldschmid.
  - Grube, 189?; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Ehrlich's draft of a telegram.
  - Herter, Christian, 1904-1910; typescript with signature and some handwritten comments (Box 1, Folder 17, 18)
    - Herter to Ehrlich, 1 letter
    - Ehrlich to Herter, undated; 15 handwritten letters and 1 block
    - Ehrlich to Herter, 12 letters
    - autobiographical notes by Ehrlich to Herter, 3 letters
    - Excerpts from letters to Herter, 9 letters, typescript
  - Idelson, Vittorio, 1911; typescript with signature (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Ehrlich's request of reprint from the Idelson Publishing Company.
  - Ilberg, 1 telegram announcing his visit to the institute, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Kahn, 1908; 1 letter typescript (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Ehrlich's comments about Kahn to some Professor.
  - Kehrman, 1909; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Kehrman to Ehrlich.
  - Kelp, (Amtsarzt), undated; 1 letter (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Scope and Contents
    handwritten note by Ehrlich requesting injections of higher doses into children
  - Keyes, Preston, 1906; 1 letter typescript copy with notations by Ehrlich Keyes to Ehrlich (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Keysser, 1912; 1 letter typescript with signature (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Letter Ehrlich to Keysser.
  - Klein, Stanislaus, typescript Klein to Ehrlich, 1914; 1 letter (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Koch, Robert, 1881 1902; 4 letters handwritten (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Koch to Ehrlich.
  - König, Walter, 1904; 1 letter typescript with signature (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Letter Ehrlich to König.
  - Krebs, Georg, bill for cigars, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 28a)
  - Kurfürsten, Apotheke, 1909; handwritten pharmacy prescription (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Landau, Leopold, 1906 1907 1914; handwritten and typescript (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Paul Ehrlich to Landau, 4 letters
    - Hedwig Ehrlich to Landau, 1 letter
  - Landau, Marianne and Edmund, undated, 29 letters (Box 1, Folder 31)
    all but one handwritten Ehrlich to the Landaus
  - Laubenheimer, 1891 August 1895 August; handwritten (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Laubenheimer to Ehrlich, 1 telegram
    - Ehrlich to Laubenheimer, 1 letter
  - Lazarus, Adolf, 1891-1902, undated; mostly handwritten (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Lazarus to Ehrlich, 1 letter
    - Ehrlich to Lazarus, 30 letters
  - Lister, Joseph, 1894-1907; 4 letters handwritten (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Lister to Ehrlich.
  - Marquardt, Martha, 1911-1915; handwritten and typed (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Marquardt to Ehrlich, 2 letters
    - Ehrlich to Marquardt, 3 letters
  - Martius, 1905; 1 letter typescript with signature (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Ehrlich to Martius.
  - Peting, (Hoflieferant), 1897; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Peting to Ehrlich.
  - Pinkus, Auguste, undated; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Ehrlich to A. Pinkus.
  - Pinkus, Joseph, 1890 1895; handwritten (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Pinkus to Hedwig Ehrlich, 1 letter
    - Pinkus to Paul Ehrlich, 1 telegram
  - Pinkus, Max, 1900; 1 letter handwritten (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Pinkus to Ehrlich.
  - Rissman, 1909 1915; handwritten and typescript copy (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Rissman to Ehrlich, 2 letters
    - Ehrlich to Rissman, 1 letter
  - Rothschild, Henri, 1914; 1 letter typescript copy (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Ehrlich to Rothschild.
  - Schmitz, (minister of education) 1900-1910, mostly handwritten (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Schmitz to Ehrlich, 5 letters
    - Ehrlich to Schmitz, 2 letters
  - Solomonson, 1898; 1 letter handwritten and typescript copy (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Ehrlich to Solomonson.
  - Contract between Speyer-Haus, 1906-1915; handwritten and typescript (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Speyer-Haus and the Vereinigte Chemische Werke dated 1906
    - Copy of a letter from the Lord Mayor of Frankfurt, dated 1921 referring to this contract
    - Financial instructions dated 1910, 1915, 2 letters
    - Notes to Ehrlich, handwritten, 2 letters
    - Calling cards of Mrs. W. von Rothschild, 2 letters
  - Spielman, 1899-1907; 7 letters handwritten (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Spielman to Ehrlich.
  - Visit to Stuttgart, 1911; 3 letters typescript (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Wassermann, 1912 August; typescript with signature (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Ehrlich to Wassermann, 1 letter
    - Contract between Ehrlich, Wassermann and Hoechst
  - Weigert, Carl, postcard to Ehrlich, 1900; handwritten (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Weizmann, Chaim, 1914; 2 letters typescript copies (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Ehrlich to Weizmann.
- Educational Records
  - Gymnasium grade book, St. Maria Magdalena, Breslau, 1864-1867 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Graduation diploma from St. Maria Magdalena Gymnasium, 1872 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Physicum - transcript from the University of Strassburg, 1874 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Doctorate diploma of the University of Leipzig, 1878 June 26 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Diploma of habilitation as Lecturer with a thesis presentation, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Über Befunde bei verschiedenen Formen von Anemien", Berlin (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Receipt for 151 Marks (habilitation fee) Berlin, 1887 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notarized copy of license to practice medicine, which Paul Ehrlich got at the time of his graduation from the University of Leipzig in 1878, 1887 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- State and Academic Appointments
  - Title of "Professor", to the then "Assistant" at the medical clinic of the University of Berlin, form letter with seal, 1882 July 31; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Title of "Asserordentlicher Professor", to the then "Privatdocent", form letter with seal and handwritten, 1890 August 16; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Announcement of salary and laboratory space at the University of Berlin in return for lectures, handwritten, 1895 November 27; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Title of "Geheimer Medicinal Rath", 1 envelope with Paul Ehrlich's handwriting addressed to Hedwig Ehrlich, in which he sent her 2 pages of a printed list of other men with the same title, with a notation that he may be the youngest. Two official letters both handwritten, 1 signed by Wilhelm II, dated Dec. 23, 1896, the other coming from the Ministerium, dated Dec. 29, 1896, 1896 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Title of "Geheimer Obermedicinal Rath", 1 letter and envelope: form letter with seal signed by Wilhelm II, 1907 December 19 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Appointment to the rectorship of the newly established University of Frankfurt and Paul Ehrlich's answer of July 10, 1914 declining, 1914 July 9; 2 items, typescript (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Handwriting analysis of Paul Ehrlich, handwritten, 5 pages only initialed, 5 pages (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Synopsis of incoming correspondence, apparently prepared by Martha Marquardt, typescript, 101 pages (Box 2, Folder 4)
  The actual correspondence is not part of this collection.
- Index of Paul Ehrlich's books which were given by his wife to the Senckenberg Library after Paul Ehrlich's death, 54 pages, typescript in alphabetical order by author (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Letters announcing memberships to national and international societies (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellschaft, Tiedman Prize, 1887 March 11; 1
  - Senckenbergische Naturforschende Gesellschaft, Corr., Member, 1887 May 10; 2
  - Balneologische Gesellschaft, Berlin Honorary Member, 1900 March 10; 3
  - Royal Danish Society of Sciences, Foreign Member, 1900 April 7; 4
  - German Chemical Society, Member of the Committee, 1902 December 13; 5
  - Academy of Medicine, Torino, Corr. Member, 1903; 6
  - Honorary Professor in the Department of Medicine, University of Gottingen, 1905 February 2; 7
  - Academy of Medicine, Paris, Foreign Member, 1905 May 23; 8
  - Royal Medical Society, Budapest, Honorary Member, 1905 December 9; 9
  - XVth International Congress of Medicine, Lisbon, award for 3000 Fcs, 1906 May 2; 10
  - Pathological Society of Great Britain and Ireland, Honorary Member, 1907 June 10; 11
  - The Society for Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, Honorary Fellow, 1907 July 9; 12
  - The Royal Institute of Public Health, London, Honorary Fellow, 1907 July 13; 13
  - Royal Academy dei Lincei, Rome, Foreign Member, 1907 August 12?; 14
  - International Commission on Nervous Diseases, Honorary Member, 1907 October 3; 15
  - The Society of Exotic Pathology (Pasteur Institute), Honorary Member, 1908 February 14; 16
  - The Physical-Medical Society, Erlangen, Honorary Member, 1908 June 27; 17
  - Society of Microbiology, St. Petersburg, Honorary Member, 1910 January 15; 18
  - German Society of Tropical Medicine, Honorary Member, 1910 October 6; 19
  - Société Khédiviale de Médecine, Cairo, Honorary Member, telegram and letter, 1910 November 7; 21
  - Odessa Society of Physicians, Honorary Member, 1910 November 7; 22
  - Int. Commission on Nervous Diseases, Honorary Member, 1910 November 20; 23